Monica Rampaul

 $416\text{-}880\text{-}4695 \cdot monicarampaul@gmail.com} \cdot www.linkedin.com/in/monica-rampaul$

Software developer with one year of experience in automation testing using Selenium WebDriver and development using object-oriented programming. Collaborated using agile methodologies in a team of 10 members through a client project at a recent experience in a high growth technology company.

Education

The University of British Columbia, Kelowna, BC

Bachelor of Arts – Major in Computer Science

Awards: Dean's List 2020 and 2021, Deputy Vice Chancellor's Scholarship 2020 and 2021.

Professional Experience

Infosys Limited, Mississauga, ON

Nov. 2022 – Sep. 2023

Associate Software Developer – SDET

- Designed 100+ sprint level test cases and regression test cases in agile teams of 10 members; increased the total number of test cases by 15%.
- Automated and executed test cases for the regression suite over 3 releases increasing automation test coverage by 10%.
- Collaborated with mentor and technical leads to improve on technical skills and build on previous dexterity to stay up to date with industry standards resulting in an increase in client project satisfaction.
- Completed 15+ technical trainings and courses over the span of 6 months leading to obtaining 3 company specific certifications.

The University of British Columbia, Kelowna, BC

Sep. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Teaching Assistant – Computer Science Department

- Instructed students in lab sessions and provided technical and non-technical support increasing lab attendance by 20%.
- Assisted students with troubleshooting software environment set up and debugging code resulting in an increase of 15% assignment passing rate.
- Reinforced students' learning by reviewing programming concepts at the beginning of lab sessions 2 times a week.
- Worked closely with course professors and teams of 5-10 teaching assistants to provide students with feedback via comments and grades for each assignment leading to deeper critical thinking practices.

Technical Projects

Ethics Dashboard / HTML5, CSS, jQuery, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, Bulma

Sep. 2021 – Apr. 2022

- Created a student ethics dashboard website for an ethics class at Okanagan College over 8 months allowing students to receive grades and feedback on case studies.
- Collaborated in a team of 4 through Github utilizing agile methods with 30-minute sprint meetings to organize development tasks.
- Communicated with and presented updates to the client resulting in a consensus within the team.
- Analyzed user testing feedback and generated progress reports, video demos, and evaluation reports every 4 weeks leading to well-structured and comprehensive deliverables for the client.

Movie Chatbot / Python, Twitter API, IMDB API, Python-Chatterbot API

Feb 2020 – Apr. 2020

- Developed a movie Chatbot that has conversations with a user about movies, cast, and directors over 3 months.
- Integrated 3 different APIs and functions resulting in 40+ possible responses generated per topic.
- Collaborated in a team of 5 members with weekly scrum meetings and sprints utilizing Github and Trello to manage developer tasks and responsibilities over the course of project.
- Authored progress and testing reports every 3 weeks resulting in stronger task management and complete and comprehensive project documentation.

Skills & Certifications

Skills

Java, Python, C, C# PHP, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, SQL, HTML Database Management Systems jUnit, TestNG, Selenium WebDriver XAMPP, LINUX, Git/Github

Certifications

Infosys Certified Cloud Testing Professional Infosys Certified Selenium Using Java Automation Testing Associate Infosys Certified Software Programmer